# Структура квиза
quiz_data = [
    {
        'question': 'Что такое Python?',
        'options': ['Язык программирования', 'Тип данных', 'Музыкальный инструмент', 'Змея на английском'],
        'correct_option': 0
    },
    {
        'question': 'Какой тип данных используется для хранения целых чисел?',
        'options': ['str', 'float', 'int', 'natural'],
        'correct_option': 2
    },
    {
        'question': 'Что такое список?',
        'options': ['Тип данных', 'Способ кодирования', 'Библиотека', 'Класс'],
        'correct_option': 0
    },
    {
        'question': 'Django - это?',
        'options': ['Библиотека', 'Фреймворк', 'Язык программирования', 'База данных'],
        'correct_option': 1
    },
    {
        'question': 'GIT - это?',
        'options': ['СУБД', 'Фреймворк', 'Язык программирования', 'СКВ'],
        'correct_option': 3
    },
    {
        'question': 'SQL - это?',
        'options': ['База данных', 'Язык запросов', 'Тип данных', 'Библиотека'],
        'correct_option': 1
    },
    {
        'question': 'Асинхронное програм.?',
        'options': ['Структура данных', 'Тип цикла', 'Метод кодирования', 'Тип ошибки'],
        'correct_option': 2
    },
    {
        'question': 'Flask - это?',
        'options': ['Библиотека', 'Фреймворк', 'Язык программирования', 'База данных'],
        'correct_option': 1
    },
    {
        'question': 'JSON - это?',
        'options': ['Формат данных', 'Библиотека', 'Язык разметки', 'Тип данных'],
        'correct_option': 0
    },
    {
        'question': 'API - это?',
        'options': ['Библиотека', 'База данных', 'Язык программирования', 'Интерфейс взаимод.'],
        'correct_option': 3
    }
    
]